A Guide to the Alice Davis Wood research notes for Alice Davis Wood research notes for Dr. Francis T. Stribling and Moral Medicine
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Alice Davis Wood research notes for Dr. Francis T. Stribling and Moral Medicine.
The Library of Virginia
45024
. 9 cubic feet and 2 boxes
Alice Davis Wood
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Alice Davis Wood of Waynesboro, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Alice Davis Wood resides in Waynesboro, Virginia. After graduating from Mary Baldwin College, she worked for General Electric Company. She served on the advisory committee for the Virginia Department of Historic Resources. Wood has three children.
Scope and Content
Research notes of Alice Davis Wood used in writing her book Dr. Francis T. Stribling and Moral Medicine: Curing the Insane at Virginia's Western State Hospital, 1836-1874. Papers include copies of Stribling's correspondence, as well as articles, deeds, pamphlets, regulations, reports, and other materials relating to Stribling and to Western State Hospital. The book was published in 2004.
Contents List
- Stribling letters--list, 1836-1874 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Stribling letters, 1844-1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Stribling letters, January-May 1857 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Stribling letters, June-December 1857 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Stribling letters, 1858-1860 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Hospital reports, 1836-1839 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Hospital reports, 1840-1845 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Hospital reports, 1848-1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Hospital reports, 1869-1873 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Hospital reports, no date (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Regulations, 1844, no date (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Regulations, 1844-1857 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Regulations, 1853(-1857) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Regulations, 1854(-1855) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Regulations, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Regulations, 1856-1857 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Regulations, 1861(-1874) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Regulations, 1862-1864 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Regulations, 1865-1866 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Regulations, 1869-1872 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Galt and admission controversy (folder 1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Galt and admission controvery (folder 2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Galt and admission controvery (folder 3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Captain Randolph incident (folder 1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Captain Randolph incident (folder 2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Captain Randolph incident (folder 3 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Captain Randolph incident (folder 4 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Hudson's experience (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Stribling obituaries and memorials (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Stribling family (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Deeds, 1832-1868 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A History of Western State Hospital (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Grandeur in the Wilderness: The Architects and Architecture of Western State Hospital and the Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Western State--A Hospital in Transition (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Western State Hospital (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Wood correspondence, 2004-2005) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- partial manuscript of book (Box 2, Folder 17)